Guide to the Walter Bordwell Papers, 1835-1929 (inclusive), 1890-1912 (bulk)
Department of Special Collections
- McDonald Tract, Los Angeles County (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Feb. 11, 1892 -Mortgage by Edward k. Blade to E.N. McDonald
  - Feb. 16, 1892 -Mortgage by Edward N. Buck to E.N. McDonald, mortgagee (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Sept. 29, 1893 -Report made at request of the German American Savings Bank
  - Apr. 11, 1894 -Continuation report made at request of German American Savings Bank
  - Nov. 16, 1894 -Limited certificate made at the request of W.S. McDonald for E.A. McDonald for the Title Insurance and Trust Company certifying that title of property is now vested in William H. Boggs
  - Nov. 16, 1894 -Limited certificate made at request of W.S. McDonald for W.M. Sheldon
  - Nov. 16, 1894 -Limited certificate made at request of E.A. McDonald for California Loan and and Trust Company
- Newell Nightingale Case (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - June 23, 1898 -WB to George Ingersoll, Jr., Att.
  - Nov. 16, 1899 -George Ingersoll, Jr., to WB
  - Dec. 9, 1899 -WB to George Ingersoll, Jr.
  - Jan. 9, 1900 -George Ingersoll, Jr., to WB
  - Jan. 26, 1901 -George Ingersoll, Jr., to WB
  - -Oct. 3, 1902 -George Ingersoll, Jr., to WB
  - Oct 13, 1902 -WB to George Ingersoll, Jr.
  - Oct. 20, 1902 -George Ingersoll to WB w/encl
  - Oct. 24, 1902 -WB to George Ingersoll, Jr.
  - Oct. 28, 1902 -WB to George Ingersoll, Jr.
  - Oct. 31, 1902 -George Ingersoll, Jr., to WB
  - Nov. 4, 1902 -Edward Kurtz, Clerk, U.S. Courts, Eastern District, Wisc., to WB
  - Dec. 22, 1902 -George Ingersoll, Jr., to WB
  - Jan. 24, 1903 -George Ingersoll, Jr., to WB
  - Feb. 4, 1903 -George Ingersoll, Jr., to WB
  - May 9, 1904 -WB to Williams, Griswold, and Chadbourne, Atts. at law
  - May 16, 1904 -Williams, Griswold, and Chadbourne to WB
  - July 17, 1905 -George Ingersoll, Jr., to WB; w/encl July 15, 1905 -Williams, Griswold, and Chadbourne to WB
  - June 6, 1906 -WB to George Ingersoll
  - June 8, 1906 -WB to George Ingersoll
  - June 23, 1906 -George Ingersoll, Jr., to WB
  - June 27, 1906 -WB to George Ingersoll, Jr.
  - Sept. 12, 1906 -George Ingersoll, Jr., to WB
- F.E. Palmer - Amanda Chubb interaction (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Sept. 26, 1895 -promise of payment to Amanda Chubb from W.A. Snidiken
  - Mar. 23, 1898 -Indenture between Amanda W. Chubb and Terese F. Spencer
  - Mar. 23, 1898 -Memoradum by Amanda Chubb transferring piano to daughter Nettie Bordull
  - Mar. 23, 1898 -Indenture between Amanda Chubb and F.E. Palmer, trustee
  - Mar. 23, 1898 -Amanda Chubb to M.N. Avery giving him deed to hold in escrow during her life
  - July 23, 1904 -F.E. Palmer to WB
  - Nov. 10, 1904 -F.E. Palmer to WB
- Tijera Creek Water Company vs. Louis Sentuos and the Union Trust and Realty Company (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - July 15, 1902 -Tijera Creek Water Co's amendments to original complaint
  - Oct. 17, 1902 -Notice of plaintiff
  - Nov. 21, 1902 -Cochran, Williams & Phillips, atts. at law, to WB
  - Nov. 25, 1902 -Cochran, Williams & Phillips, atts. at law, to WB
- Helena Granger vs. Henry Robinson (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Apr. 25, 1892 -Witness of bonds pledged from Henry W. Robinson and John C. Dixon to Helena M. Granger
  - Jun. 26, 1893 -Riverside County, CA assessment list
  - Dec. 21, 1893 -Certificate of Search of Property of Henry W. Robinson
  - Dec. 29, 1893 -Memorandum of agreement between Helen M. Granger and John Dixon
  - Jan. 1894 -Deed of Trust made between Henry W. Robinson and Eliza A. Robinson
  - Jan. 7, 1894 -Groendyke and Moore, investment brokers, to WB
  - Jan. 12, 1894 -Memorandum of Agreement between H.M. Granger and H.W. Robinson (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Jan. 12, 1894 -Mortgage by Henry W. Robinson and Eliza A. Robinson to Helena Granger
  - Jan. 12, 1894 -Witness of pledge from H.W. Robinson to Helena M. Granger
  - Jan. 12, 1894 -Memorandum, Granger vs. Robinson
  - Jan. 19, 1894 -E.W. Dawson to WB
  - Jan. 24, 1894 -E.W. Dawson to WB
  - Sept. 1, 1894 -Statement from Abstract and Guaranty Co. (Riverside) case
  - Nov. 7, 1894 -Notice of Action
  - Nov. 9, 1894 -Sweesy and Grow, Abstract Company to WB
  - Feb. 21, 1895 -Shirley Ward, of the German American Insurance Co. to WB
  - Mar. 1, 1895 -complaints of Helena M. Granger (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Mar. 5, 1895 -Notice of right to redeem property from A.H. Seccombe to H.M. Granger
  - Mar. 14, 1895 -J.P. Scott to WB
  - Mar. 25, 1895 -J.P. Scott to WB
  - Apr. 12, 1895 -F.H. Bowman to WB
  - May 4, 1895 -J.P. Scott to WB
  - May 16, 1895 -F.H. Bowman to WB
  - July, 1895 -Notice of right to redeem property from A.H. Seccombe to H.M. Granger
  - July 18, 1895 -A.J. Condee, Riverside County Clerk to WB
  - July 19, 1895 -Notice to C.C. Haskell from WB that court has overruled the Demurrer of defendant
  - July 27, 1895 -Answers of Eliza A. Robinson to plaintiff's complaint
  - July 29, 1895 -Answers of Obed Bernard to plaintiff's complaint
  - Aug. 6, 1895 -Memorandum of agreement made between R.W.A. Godfrey and Helena M. Granger, (2 copies) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Aug. 15, 1895 -A.J. Condee to WB
  - Sept. 13, 1895 -F.A. Leonard to WB
  - Sept. 16, 1895 -Telegraph from C.C. Haskell to WB
  - Aug. 29, 1895 -Civil subpoena to Eliza A. Robinson, (2 copies)
  - Oct. 4, 1895 -Answers of H.W. Robinson
  - Nov., 1895 -Motion to Strike Out by Eliza A. Robinson
  - Nov, 1895 -Motion to Strike Out by H.W. Robinson, (2 copies)
  - Nov. 13, 1895 -C.C. Haskell to WB
  - Nov., 1895 -Affidavit
  - Dec. 2, 1895 -Subpoena for Deposition of Obed Bernard
  - Dec. 2, 1895 -Amended answers of Obed Bernard
  - Dec. 2, 1895 -Notice and Affadavit of Eliza A. Robinson, Obed Bernard, C.C. Haskell, and Henry Robinson
  - Dec. 4, 1895 -Findings of Granger vs. Robinson
  - Dec. 4, 1895 -Engrossed Statement by H.W. Robinson on motion for a new trial
  - Dec. 4, 1895 -Amended answers of H.W. Robinson (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dec. 4, 1895 -Statement on motion for a new trial by Helena Granger, (2 copies)
  - Dec. 4, 1895 -Telegraph from G.F. Granger to WB
  - Dec. 6, 1895 -Notice of Commissioner's sale of foreclosure of mortgage, (3 copies)
  - Dec. 6, 1895 -Bill of Sale from William Matthews
  - Dec. 14, 1895 -Notice of Intention to move for a new trial, (2 copies)
  - Dec. 26, 1895 -H. Foster to WB
  - Dec. 28, 1895 -H. Foster to WB (wo/encl)
  - Dec. 28, 1895 -Telegraph from H.W. Robinson to G.F. Granger
  - Dec. 28, 1895 -Henry W. Robinson to H. M. Granger
  - Dec. 30, 1895 -Notice of amendments from H.M. Granger to proposed statement for a new trial
  - Jan. 1, 1896 -Notice of received payment from Kate Lane to WB (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Jan. 2, 1896 -Notice that proposed amendments are not adopted, Eliza and Henry Robinson to Helena Granger, (3 copies)
  - Jan. 2, 1896 -Notice of Writ of Execution
  - Jan. 2, 1896 -Copy of Execution
  - Jan. 3, 1896 -J.S. Noyes, Riverside, CA, superior judge, to WB
  - Jan. 6, 1896 -Herb Foster to WB
  - Jan. 8, 1896 -A.J. Condee, Riverside County clerk
  - Jan. 10, 1896 -E. Lacy, Riverside County Deputy Sheriff, to WB
  - Jan. 13, 1896 -Complaint of Helena M. Granger
  - Jan. 23, 1896 -Herb C. Foster to WB
  - Feb. 5, 1896 -G.F. Granger to WB
  - Feb. 15, 1896 -Brief on behalf of H.M. Granger in reply to Robinson's motion of a new trial
  - Feb. 26, 1896 -Edward Lacy, Riverside County Deputy Sheriff to WB
  - Feb. 29, 1896 -W.A. Purington, Att., to WB
  - Mar. 3, 1896 -Telegraph from J.S. Noyes to WB
  - Mar. 11, 1896 -Notice of binding payment from WB and George F. Granger to F.L. Holcomb
  - Mar. 13, 1896 -WB to H.T. Haynes
  - Mar. 13, 1896 -W.B. Clancy, Riverside County auditor, to WB, w/redemption receipt
  - Mar. 16, 1896 -Edward Lacy, Riverside County deputy sheriff to wB
  - Mar. 19, 1896 -F.L. Holcomb to WB
  - Mar. 21, 1896 -Purington & Adair, atts. at law, to WB
  - Mar. 21, 1896 -Subpoena for Deposition of Obed Bernard
  - Mar. 21, 1896 -Henry Ingram to WB
  - Mar. 21, 1896 -Purington & Adair, atts. at law, to WB (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Mar. 21, 1896 -Subpoena for Deposition of Obed Bernard
  - Mar. 24, 1896 -First National Bank of L.A. Ass't cashier G.B. Shaffer to WB, w/encl of Mar. 9, 1896 - Purington & Adair to WB
  - Mar. 28, 1896 -Notice to Redeem to H.W. Robinson and H. M. Granger by Obed Bernard
  - Mar. 28, 1896 -F.A. Leonard to WB
  - Mar. 30, 1896 -Statement of Sheriff's fees from W.B. Johnson, Sheriff, to WB
  - Mar. 30, 1896 -Edward Lacy to WB (w/o encl)
  - Apr. 1, 1896 -E.P. Clark, Riverside Daily Press business manager to WB
  - Apr. 9, 1896 -WB to M.V. Sweesy, att. at law
  - Apr. 10, 1896 -Goodcell and Leonard to WB
  - Apr. 13, 1896 -Statement of Sheriff's fees to WB from H.L. Holcomb, Sheriff of Riverside County
  - May 1, 1896 -Publish notice from The Saturday Review, San Bernardino county to WB
  - May 2, 1896 -Notice of H. Robinson's appeal to H. Granger and WB, (2 copies)
  - June 1, 1896 -Receipt from The Staurday Review to WB
  - June 10, 1896 -H. (?), att. for H. Robinson to WB
  - July 1, 1896 -Indenture between William B. Matthews, commissioner, and H.M. Granger
  - July 9, 1896 -Walter Wagner, San Bernardino County deputy audior, to WB
  - July 11, 1896 -H.T. Hayes to WB
  - July 18, 1896 -W.A. Purington to WB
  - Aug. 1896 -Affidavit
  - Aug. 5, 1896 -J.W. Roberts, Riverside County Deputy to WB
  - Aug. 7, 1896 -F.A. Leonard to WB
  - Aug. 8, 1896 -Bill from Chas. W. Palm Printing Company to WB
  - Aug. 12, 1896 -Receipt to WB from State of California Supreme Court
  - Aug. 1896(Inc'd) - Justification of Sureties of Appeal bond
  - Oct. 9, 1896 -Stipulation
  - Oct. 9, 1896 -WB to Mr. M.V. Sweesy
  - Oct. 10, 1896 -F.A. Leonard to WB
  - Dec. 2, 1896 -Statement of Sheriff's fees from William Roach to WB
  - Dec. 22, 1896 - -W.A. Purington to WB
  - Jan. 9, 1897 - -W.A. Purington to WB
  - Jan. 27, 1897 -WB to E.R. Hull
  - Feb. 2, 1897 -E.R. Hull to WB
  - Feb. 11, 1897 -E.R. Hull to WB
  - Feb. 15, 1897 -H. Conner to WB
  - Mar. 29, 1897 -W.A. Purington to WB
  - Nov. 13, 1897 -WB to A.R. Metcalf
  - Nov. 22, 1897 -Orowell (?) to WB
  - Dec. 17, 1897 -M.V. Sweesy to WB
  - Mar. 16, 1898 -J.W.F. Diss, San Bernardino County auditor to WB
  - Apr. 1, 1898 -Stipulation of case dismissal
  - May 24, 1898 -A.J. Condee to WB
  - Mar. 28, 1900 -Stipulation for dismissal
  - n.d. -Suggestions (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - n.d. -Notice to H.W. Robinson from WB
  - n.d. -Demurrer of H.W. Robinson
  - n.d. -Opinion of Judge Noyse
  - n.d. -Demurrer of Obed Bernard, (2 copies)
  - n.d. -Appeal Bonds
  - n.d. -Instructions to Sheriff of San Bernardino County from WB
  - n.d. -Memorandum
  - n.d. -Notice
  - n.d. -Brief on behalf of Plaintiff in reply to Brief of Defendant, Eliza A. Robinson, on her motion for a new trial
  - n.d. -Instructions to Sheriff of San Bernardino County
  - n.d. -Notice of Execution
  - n.d. -Stipulation
  - n.d. -Notice of Execution (6 copies) from Sheriff of Riverside County
  - n.d. -Subpoena of Eliza A. Robinson
  - n.d. -Reply Brief on behalf of Defendant Eliza A. Robinson on motion for a new trial
  - n.d. -Motion to dismiss appeal by WB, (3 copies) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - n.d. -Notice of Action
  - n.d. -Answers of Obed Bernard
  - n.d. -Complaint of Eliza A. Robinson
  - n.d. -Deposition of Eliza A. Robinson
  - n.d. -Demurrer of H.M. Granger, F.L. Holcomb and George F. Granger
  - n.d. -Memorandum of points on behalf of the Defendants, Grangers and Holcomb, in support of their Demurrer
  - n.d. -Dpeosition of Obed Bernard and Eliza A. Robinson
  - n.d. -Amended answers of Obed Bernard
  - n.d. -Defendant Eliza A. Robinson Brief on motion for a new trial
- McNamara Trial (Burning of the L.A. Times Building) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Judge's Notes - book of notes taken by Judge Walter Bordwell during the course of the trial
- Miscellaneous Correspondence in Response to Investigation (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Oct. 25, 1910 -Anonymous (L.A.) to the Grand Jury of the Times Investigation
  - Nov. 12, 1910 -Anonymous (L.A.) to the Grand Jury Investigation
  - June 7, 1911 -Marietta Businessmen and Socialist members to Governor of Indiana
  - Aug. 5, 1911 - A Soldier for Jesus (Denver) to WB
  - Aug. 10, 1911 - The Committee (Kansas City) to WB
  - Nov. 15, 1911 -Postcard from the Progressives of N.Y. to WB
  - Dec. 3, 1911 -William Sproul (Penn.) with newspaper article to WB
  - Dec. 4, 1911 -Mr. John A. McNamara (Father of J.J. and J.B. McNamara) (Chicago) to WB (plus copy)
  - Dec. 8, 1911 -WB to Mr. John McNamara
  - Dec. 6, 1911 -Wallace (?), Omaha National Bank, to WB
  - Dec. 6, 1911 -C.L. Nourse (Des Moines) to WB
  - Dec. 6, 1911 -O.P. Briggs (Minneapolis) to WB
  - Dec. 6, 1911 -John L. Moon (Oklahoma City) to WB (letter, business card, and newspaper clipping)
  - Dec. 5, 1911 -Mother of Frank Underwood (Peoria, Ill) to WB (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Dec. 6, 1911 -R.L. Warner (Boston) to WB
  - Dec. 7, 1911 -J.W. Morris (Spokane) to WB
  - Dec. 7, 1911 -O.W. Dawson, Mayor, (Great Bend, Kansas) to WB
  - Dec. 8, 1911 -David F. Bonner, Minister (Endicott, N.Y.) to WB
  - Dec. 8, 1911 -E.A. Chase (Riverside, CA) to WB
  - Dec. 10, 1911 -K.C. Hon (?) to WB - newspaper clipping
  - Dec. 12, 1911 -No name (L.A.) to WB - newspaper clipping
  - Dec. 23, 1911 -Judge James W. Bartlett (CA) to WB
  - Dec. 25, 1911 -Harrison Otis (L.A.) to WB
- Grand Jury Reports, Affidavits, Depositions, etc. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Jan. 5, 1911 -L.A. Grand Jury Report on Investigation of the L.A. times disaster
  - Oct. 5, and Oct. 7, 1911 -Conversation between Mr. Davis, Judge McNutt, Mr. Darrow, Mr. Scott and Judge Bordwell, (2 copies)
  - Oct. 11, 1911 -Plaintiff's Affadavit on Defendents' motion to transfer case to another department or another judge
  - Oct. 13, 1911 -Final Report of the Los Angeles County Grand Jury introduction sheet w/o actual report
  - Feb. 23, 1912 -Deposition of Job Harriman
  - Sept. 3, 1912 -J.H. Levering to WN
  - Miscellaneous notes and rough drafts
    - Jan. 1911 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - July 25, 1911 - Oct. 28, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Nov. 1, 1911 - Dec. 5, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Dec. 5, 1911 - Dec. 7, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Newspaper Clippings
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1911, 1912, 1929? (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 8, Folder 1-17)